《太空堡垒卡拉狄加》前情回顾
NARRATOR: Previously on Battlestar Galactica.
在你那所谓的潜意识深处
Deep down in that thing you call a subconscious,
你知道在舰队里还有多少个赛昂人
you know how many Cylons there are left in the fleet.
8个  有8个
Eight! There are eight!
温纳下士报告前任总统失踪
Cpl. Venner reports the former President's missing.
失踪?  两人受伤  牢里没人
Missing? Two men down, cell's empty.
该死的
Damn it.
很高兴见到你  总统女士
ZAREK: Glad to see you, Madam President.
泽瑞克先生  看来我敌人的敌人就是我的朋友了
Well, Mr. Zarek. It would seem the enemy of my enemy is my friend.
去找地球
Go find Earth.
我们回家吧
Let's go home.
我们已经发现了科波
ROSLIN: We have found Kobol.
当我们获得神箭之后将打开雅典娜之墓
And when we retrieve the Arrow, we will open the Tomb of Athena
我们将找到通往地球的道路
and we will find the road to Earth.
没人会相信这鬼话
No one's gonna believe this crap.
如果有人想回到科波自寻死路的话  让他们去吧
And anyone that wants to make a suicide run to Kobol, let them.
星际女皇跳跃走了
Astral Queen has jumped away.
24艘  长官
GAETA: Twenty-four ships, sir.
几乎是三分之一的舰队了
That's almost a third of the fleet.
他们要追随罗丝琳去科波自取灭亡
They're gonna follow Roslin to Kobol to their death.
24艘船上的18000人
DUALLA: 18,000 souls aboard the 24 ships
加入了前任总统罗丝琳的叛军
that joined former President Roslin's rebellion, sir.
这可超过了舰队里三分之一的民众
TIGH: That's over a third of the people in the fleet.
给我一份名单  我们的损失有哪些?
Give me a breakdown. What have we lost?
杰米纳的9500人  卡布里卡的6250人
DUALLA: 9,500 souls from Gemenon, 6,250 from Caprica.
不是损失了谁  而是损失了什么
Not who. What.
我对那些决定加入
I'm not interested in people who decide to join up
狂热宗教徒和恐怖份子的人没兴趣
with a religious fanatic and a terrorist.
那是他们的事  我们损失了什么?
That's their business. Now, what have I lost?
12艘运输船  7艘货船  3艘基建船
12 transports, seven freighters, three construction platforms,
1艘私人巡航舰  1艘采矿船  长官
a private cruiser and a mining ship, sir.
君王统治可不好
The Monarch was a blow.
我们承担不起损失采矿船的代价 至少当前不行
We can't afford to lose mining ships, not in our situation.
这还会引起一些间接问题
And then there's the collateral damage.
整个舰队士气会下降
Morale is down throughout the fleet.
媒体会大肆宣扬  家人被分开
The press is going wild, families are being split apart...
别和我谈家人
Don't talk to me about family.
我完全支持总统
APOLLO: I support the president completely.
我的首要职责就是保护她的人身安全
And my only priorities are the preservation of her safety
和完成此次任务
and the completion of this mission.
说得都不错  但他仍旧是阿达玛的儿子
That's all well and good, but he's still Adama's son.
是啊  对
MAN: Yeah! WOMAN: Yes!
到了关键时刻  我们怎么知道他愿意
When push comes to shove, how do we know he'll be willing to stand up...
如果不是有他在 我还在卡拉狄加的牢房里
If it were not for him, I would still be in a Galactica jail cell.
我完全信任他  这个问题到此为止
I trust him completely and this subject is closed.
那卡拉狄加怎么办?
And what about Galactica?
他们知道我们在哪里
They know where we are.
他们随时可以跳跃到这里  然后指控我们叛国
They could jump in here at any time and charge us all with treason
或是轻而易举地摧毁我们
or destroy this ship with a flick of the wrist.
我们并非毫无防备
ZAREK: We're not entirely defenseless.
我们当中的一些船是配有武器的
Some of our ships are armed.
为了以防万一  我们应该武装其他船只
We should take steps to arm the others, just in case.
除非我们想自杀!
Just in case we want to commit suicide.
如果卡拉狄加想干掉我们 我们无能为力
If Galactica wants to take us down, there is nothing we can do about it.
只能任人宰割
Nothing.
这个房间里的每个人都不该去痴心妄想
And nobody in this room should be under any illusions on that count.
到了这时候 我确信阿达玛指挥官已经放我们走了
At this point, it's my firm belief that Cdr. Adama has let us go.
瑟瑞丝中尉将回来
Lt. Thrace will return.
她会带着 阿波罗之箭 回来
She will have the Arrow of Apollo
神箭将会帮我们找到去地球的道路
and it will help us find our way to Earth.
我们到底还要等她多久?
And exactly how long should we wait for her?
也许我们现在就该到科波上
I mean, maybe we should go down to the surface now.
开始寻找这个古墓
Go down now and start looking for this tomb.
不要那么急  那里可能还有赛昂人
I wouldn't be too eager. There may still be Cylons present.
我们中的一些人会死在那里
And some of us will die down there.
经文上说任何回到科波的人...
The scriptures tell us that any return to Kobol
都付出了代价
carries with it a cost
血的代价
in blood.
各位
People,
我知道还有很多问题有待答复
I realize that there are still many unanswered questions here.
但我不会丢掉大局观
But I refuse to lose sight of what this has always been about:
我们的任务是挽救人类
Our mission to save humanity.
是的  这是一个大任务
Yes, it's a big one.
但这是我们命中注定的
But it is our foretold destiny
作为我个人来讲  从现在开始不会动摇
and I, for one, am not going to waver from it now.
如果在座各位无意参与这项任务
If there is anyone here who does not have the stomach for this mission,
欢送你们去重新加入阿达玛指挥官的舰队
you are welcome to rejoin Cdr. Adama's fleet.
它两分钟前跳跃进了雷达监视范围
It jumped into dradis range about two minutes ago.
没有殖民舰队的应答器 对于赛昂突袭机来说也过于庞大
No Colonial transponder, and it's too large to be Thrace's Cylon Raider.
对我们的招呼也没反应?
And no response to our hails?
一声都没有  汤姆
MEIER: Not a peep, Tom.
它不是赛昂人的飞船 就是卡拉狄加派来的猛禽侦察机
It's either a Cylon vessel, or it's a Raptor scout from Galactica.
反正我们都该先开火再说
Either way, we should shoot first and ask questions later.
是这样啊
Okay.
它在亚得里亚号 的射程内 我们有舰对舰导弹
The Adriatic is in weapons range and she's got ship-to-ship missiles.
汤姆  那东西速度很快
Tom, that thing is moving fast.
我们得把它击落  最好把它打下来
If we're gonna shoot it down, we better shoot it down.
要把什么打下来?
Shoot what down?
还用我再问一遍吗?
Do I have to repeat myself?
总统女士  我们有个安全问题 仅此而已
Madam President, we have a security situation, that's all.
她不是和你说话
She wasn't talking to you.
有一艘不明飞船向我们驶来
There's an unidentified ship making its way towards us.
太大了  不可能是中尉的赛昂突袭机
ZAREK: It's too big to be the Lieutenant's Cylon Raider.
它在射程内  亚得里亚号必须立即发射导弹了
It's in weapons range. The Adriatic has to fire her missiles now.
我们需要做出抉择  总统女士
We need a decision, Madam President.
民用船  民用船
STARBUCK ON RADIO: Civilian vessels, civilian vessels,
我是星芭儿  你收到了吗?
this is Starbuck, do you read?
收到了吗? 重复一遍  我是星芭儿
Do you read? Say again, this is Starbuck.
有人收到吗?
Is anybody getting this?
有人吗?
Hello?
开始入港
MAN ON RADIO: Initiate docking.
很高兴见到你  上尉
Good to see you, too, Captain.
一会儿提醒我把你送到禁闭室去
Remind me to send you to the brig later.
恩
Yeah, well.
中尉
Lieutenant.
李  有些事我要和你说
Lee, there's something I need to tell you.
李!等下!
Lee, wait!
你他妈动一动试试!
Don't you frakking move!
别这样!她是自己人!
Stop! She's with us.
放下你的武器  长官
Drop your weapon, sir.
放下你的武器  西洛
Drop your weapon. Helo.
各位  我只说一次
Gentlemen, I'm only going to say this once.
阿达玛上尉  还有你叫什么名字?
Capt. Adama, and... What is your name?
阿格森中尉
Lt. Agathon.
以前是莎伦的电子干扰员
APOLLO: He used to be Sharon's ECO.
我以为你死了  西洛  你也是赛昂人吗?
I thought you were dead, Helo. You a Cylon, too?
连想都别想
Don't even...
好了  按我说的做
All right, here's what we're gonna do.
你们都把枪放下 我说的话听清楚了吗?
You're gonna lower your weapons. Am I being perfectly clear?
那莎伦呢?
What about Sharon?
她会被带进牢房
She will be taken to a holding cell,
安全无事
where she will remain unharmed.
好  怎么样  阿波罗?
HELO: Okay. How about it, Apollo?
我们该听那位好好女士的吗?
Should we do what the nice lady says?
她是殖民地的总统  你个白痴
She's the President of the Colonies, you moron.
是的  我们就按她说的做
And yes, we're gonna do exactly what she says.
立即放下武器
Lower your weapons, now.
谢谢
ROSLIN: Thank you.
现在把那东西放进过度舱
Now, put that thing out the airlock.
什么?
What?
我们不会把赛昂人留在这里  中尉
We don't keep Cylons around here, Lieutenant.
怎么他妈回事? 你说过了不会伤害她
What the frak? You said you weren't gonna hurt her!
西洛!听我说!
APOLLO: Hey, Helo! Listen to me!
其中的一个复制体向我父亲的胸部开了两枪!
One of those things put two rounds into my father's chest.
不是我干的!    阿达玛中枪了?
It wasn't me! Adama was shot?
是的
APOLLO: Yes.
你们错过了一些大劫难
You missed a few catastrophes while you were away.
请告诉我她还活着  是的
Please tell me he's alive. Yes.
经过了两次急救手术 卡托保住了他的性命
After two emergency surgeries, Cottle managed to save him.
不是我干的!
BOOMER: That wasn't me.
卡拉!
Kara!
看在神的份上     等等  等下
For the love of gods. BOOMER: Wait! Listen!
这个莎伦可在卡布里卡救过我们    告诉他们啊!
Sharon, this Sharon, saved our lives back on Caprica. Tell them.
告诉他们啊!
Tell them.
我知道怎么找到 雅典娜之墓      你们知道吗?
I know how to find the Tomb of Athena. Do you?
科波是个大星球
Kobol's a big planet.
你找不到古墓  就找不到地球
You don't find the Tomb, you don't find Earth.
听她的吧  看在神的份上
Listen to her, for gods' sakes.
听我说!
Listen to me!
总统女士
Madam President.
告诉他们等一下
Tell them to wait a minute.
是  先生
AIDE: Yes, sir.
谢谢你
Thank you.
泽瑞克先生  是否有地方能让我和那位年轻的女子谈一下?
Mr. Zarek, is there someplace where that young woman and I can speak?
我可以安排
I can arrange that.
很高兴又见到你  卡拉
It's great to see you again, Kara.
多谢你带来了垃圾
Thanks for bringing in the trash.
看来我们错过好戏了
Looks like we missed all the fun.
佩里
Perry?
不行
No.
缪勒  缪勒也是个不错的选择
Well, Mueller. Mueller's not a bad choice.
他作为飞行编队的副长
TIGH: He did a tour as a squadron XO.
缪勒总不知足
Mueller's a malcontent.
我知道你不想听
I know you don't want to hear this,
可这一堆里没有另外一个阿波罗了
but there is not another Apollo in this bunch
但我们还得选出一名新的空军指挥官
and we do have to pick a new CAG.
阿达玛指挥官
BIRCH: Cdr. Adama.
伯奇中尉  请进
Lt. Birch. Please, come in.
感谢你临时前来
Thank you for coming in such short notice.
没问题  长官
Of course, sir.
我想你已经注意到了舰队里的一些调整
I'm sure you're aware there's been a change in the fleet.
我们的几名驾驶员离开了
Several of our pilots departed.
而我们需要一名新的空军指挥官来填补空缺
I was just thinking that we needed a new CAG to step up.
那是当然  长官
Absolutely, sir.
会是谁呢?
Who's it going to be?
恭喜你  上尉
Congratulations, Captain.
是你
It's you.
谢谢  长官
Thank you, sir.
我和整个团队都会支持你
I just want you to know you have total support of myself and this entire crew.
是吧  上校?
Is that not right, Colonel?
绝对是的
Absolutely.
拿好你的值班日记薄
Here's your log book.
恭喜
Congratulations.
这是我的荣幸  长官 我不会让你失望的
I'm honored, Commander. I won't let you down.
我还想说的是 我是你儿子的忠实支持者
And sir, I'd just like to say that I was a tremendous supporter of your son.
阿达玛上尉  他是一位优秀的队长  长官
Capt. Adama. He was a great leader, sir.
一艘船就是一个家庭
A ship is a family.
一切都是建立在信任 理解和关爱之上的
It works on trust, understanding, and love.
我对船员的爱和对我的...
I love everyone on this ship as much as I love my...
儿子们的爱是一样多的
My sons.
卡拉狄加仍旧是一个家庭 你是家中的要员
Galactica is still a family. You're an important part of that family.
明白吗?
Do you understand?
是的  长官
Yes, sir.
多谢  乔治  我相信你会干得不错
Thank you, George. I'm sure you'll do a fine job.
怎么回事?    你让我来选新的空军指挥官
What the hell? You got me in here jawing about picking a new CAG
你自己却早选定了
and you've already made your choice?
我只是想看看我们是否意见一致
I just wanted to see if you and I were on the same page or not.
什么?
I beg your pardon?
看来不一致  你说对了
I guess we're not. You guessed right.
你是说那孩子是当领导的材料吗?
You're telling me that kid is leadership material?
选择不多  他已经是其中最好的了
We have very few choices and he's the best.
他是一个好人  索尔
He's a good man, Saul.
诚实  忠诚
He's honest and he's loyal.
我们现在需要这种人
We need a little bit of that around here right now.
你的决定  我支持
Well, it's your call. I'll support it.
指挥官
Commander.
阿达玛指挥官
ALL: Cdr. Adama!
你能就…
Can you tell us about...
能对劳拉·罗丝琳一事发表一下评论吗?
Can you make any comments regarding Laura Roslin...
这东西还好用吗?    各位请坐
This thing working? Please be seated.
你最终会签署那些命令吗
FEMALE REPORTER: Will you be finally addressing those issues?
指挥官  你是否会对…
FEMALE REPORTER: Commander, will you be responding...
请允许我发表一份声明
Allow me to make a statement, please.
请允许我发表一份声明  各位请坐
Please allow me to make a statement. Please be seated.
非常感谢
Thank you very much.
或许各位还不知道  舰队已分裂了
If you don't already know, the fleet has been divided.
等等
ADAMA: Wait!
我们同为失去伙伴而感到难过
We share the grief of friends lost.
我们所失去的能源
And the resources we've sacrificed
将带给我们大家全新的挑战
will present new challenges for all of us.
但如果我们团结在一起
But if we stay together,
就会取得同从前一样实力
we will rise to the occasion as we have before.
可以提问了
Questions? ALL: Here!
请
Yes?
你知道坐标方位
Do you know the coordinates,
知道罗丝琳总统的叛军位置吗
the whereabouts of President Roslin's rebellion?
你打算让舰队重新聚合到一起吗?
Do you intend to put the fleet back together?
首先  劳拉·罗丝琳已不是总统了
First of all, Laura Roslin is no longer president.
当她在这艘船上发动兵变的时候 就已经放弃了这个角色
She relinquished that role when she suborned mutiny aboard this ship.
下一个问题
Next question.
可  但是指挥官    指挥官
But, Commander... Commander...
恩  你说吧
Yes, go ahead.
因为舰队已经分裂
MALE REPORTER: Since the fleet has been divided...
指挥官  你还没回答我的问题
Commander, you haven't answered my question yet.
我们并没有失去任何不可以被忠诚人员取而代之的人
We have lost no one that cannot be replaced by someone loyal
而这些忠诚的人选择了和我们在一起
who has chosen to remain with us.
这就是舰队
This is the fleet.
谢谢
Thank you.
这就是舰队?
This is the fleet?
指挥官!指挥官!
MALE REPORTER: Commander? Commander?
传言所说根本就没有地球
Is there any truth to the rumor that there is no Earth,
是你编造出来的 这些是否属实呢?
it doesn't exist and you just made it up?
那叫什么问题?
What the hell kind of question is that?
无线电里传遍了 时事通讯和书信上也有说
It's been all over talk wireless, newsletter circuit, hand mail.
新闻自由并不意味着任意诽谤
Freedom of the press is not a license to slander.
传播那样的鬼话
Broadcasting that kind of garbage
只能让你快点进牢房
is the quickest way to find yourself in a holding cell.
你们全都如此
That goes for all of you.
到此为止
TIGH: We're done here.
把手拿开
Get your hands off me.
冷静一下
Why don't you calm down?
下次提醒我别再干这种活
Remind me not to do that again.
罗丝琳这么做的时候总是满脸轻松
Always looked easy enough when Roslin did it.
在欧几里德河上曾有一座步行桥
There was an old footbridge over the Euclid River.
当我还是个孩子的时候我常去那里
I used to go there when I was a boy.
看鱼儿们挣扎着向上游去
Watch the fish try and swim upstream.
它们令人着迷
They were mesmerizing.
我羡慕它们
I envied them,
并未意识到它们的生活...
unaware as they were of the
更加错综复杂且充满挑战
wider complexities, challenges of life.
你开始以我们的视角看待人类了
You're beginning to see human beings as we see them.
我开始看到的是一张张赛昂人的脸  无处不在
What I am beginning to see are Cylon faces, everywhere I look.
莎伦说舰队里还有8个赛昂人
Sharon told me there were eight Cylons left in the fleet.
我怎么就没问她是谁呢?
Why didn't I ask her who they were?
如果不是那个白痴杀了她
If that idiot hadn't shot her.
为什么事情一变糟    就糟糕成这样?
And why is it when things go wrong, they go wrong so well...
盖尤斯  这些事你想得太多啦
Gaius, you get yourself far, far too worked up about these things.
他们倒是一身轻松  不是吗?
They do have it easy, don't they?
他们?
They?
为什么你对我说话的语气 好像我不是他们中的一员一样
Why are you talking to me like I'm not one of them?
从某些方面讲 你从未是他们中的一员
In some ways, you never were.
你有你的宿命
You have a path.
你会拯救他们的命运
You will be spared their fate.
这一次  盖尤斯  你不用再操纵世界
For once, Gaius, you can stop manipulating the world
而让宿命来决定这一切
and let destiny take its course.
如果我们对人类的了解有一件事是可以肯定的话
If there's one thing we know about human beings with certainty,
那就是...他们是自毁的先师
they are masters of self-destruction.
因为我爱他
Because I love him.
还因为我怀着他的孩子
And because I'm carrying his child.
我明白了  这样就合理了
Oh, I see, that explains it.
你在这里的原因并不是因为你对我们有害
You're not here because you mean us any harm,
或是天生就被编程是人类的敌人
or because you're a programmed enemy of humanity.
而是因为你和我们的一位猛禽号驾驶员有染
You're here because you had an affair with one of our Raptor pilots.
听我说    我在听你说
Listen to me. I'm listening to you.
我现在听信一个赛昂人的话 本身就是一个错误
That's my mistake. I'm listening to a Cylon.
我在这里是因为我选择要来这里
I am here because I chose to come here.
我知道你不信任我
And I know you don't believe me.
但听好了  即便是你找到了古墓
But hear this, even if you find the Tomb,
找到了那地图  找到了地球
even if you find the map, and even if you find Earth,
你所要付出的代价将会很高
the price you pay will be too high.
我对你的预言没兴趣
I'm not interested in your prophecies.
我知道科波上有赛昂军队  我知道很危险
I know that there is a Cylon force on Kobol. I know it's dangerous.
我还有点怀疑在我们谈话的时候
And I have little doubt that you are communicating everything I say
你还在和其他人联系
even as we speak.
不是那样的 我并没尝试去联系
It doesn't work like that. I'm not wired in.
莎伦  很简单
Sharon, it's simple.
我想知道并且能保住你性命的事
What I need to know and what might keep you alive,
就是怎么找到雅典娜之墓
is exactly how to find the Tomb of Athena.
给我一张地图
Get me a map
我会尽力找出怎样到达古墓
and I will do my best to tell you how to get to the Tomb.
不  不光要尽力
No, you'll do better than your best.
我要知道它在哪里  你知不知道
I want to know where it is and you either know or you don't.
我们都知道古墓在哪里
We all know about the Tomb.
我可以为你指出那条路
I can show you the path.
我不知道那条路有多长或是通向哪里
I don't know how long the path is, or exactly where it leads to,
但可以肯定的是你们要动作快
but I can tell you that you're gonna have to move very, very quickly.
她声称她爱阿格森中尉
She claims to love Lt. Agathon.
她说她爱她所怀的孩子
She says she loves the baby she's carrying.
谁在乎她说些什么
Who cares what she says?
你不能相信她所说的每句
You can't believe a word, any of them.
帕蒂亚的圣轴上确实说过在危急时刻
The scrolls of Pythia do speak of a lower demon
一个下等的恶魔会帮助人类
who helped the people in a time of crisis.
还是迷信
More superstition.
我告诉她除非我们从科波 带回来指明地球方位的地图
I've told her that unless we return from Kobol with a map to Earth,
不然阿格森中尉就会作为 与赛昂人通敌份子被送进过度舱
that Lt. Agathon will be put out the airlock as a Cylon conspirator.
是真的吗?
Is that true?
不管是真是假  反正她相信了
Doesn't matter if it's true. She believed it.
她救了他和孩子  她不用这么做的
She saved them, both of them. She didn't have to.
她可以救她的孩子  而让他去送死 可她为什么没那么做?
She could've saved her child and let them die. Why didn't she?
因为我相信她有一件事说的是真的
Because I believe that she's telling the truth about one thing,
她自以为她恋爱了
she thinks she's in love.
即使是用程序代替了感情 但对她来说还是真实的
Even if it's software instead of an emotion, it's real to her.
她想让她的孩子活下来 想让阿格森活下来
She wants her baby to live. She wants Agathon to live.
我们利用了这点
We use that.
这不是我想看到的局面
This is not the way that I thought things were gonna go down.
我知道他们会怀疑  但...
I knew they'd be suspicious, but...
他们是人类
They're human,
和你一样
the way you are.
是否有人想过
Has anyone stopped to consider
莎伦这么了解科波 就是因为这是赛昂人所设的陷阱
that the reason Sharon knows so much about Kobol is because it's a Cylon trap?
我早想过了
I've done more than consider it.
很可能这是赛昂人所设的陷阱
It is clearly possible we're facing a trap.
阿波罗上尉已经警告过我们
Capt. Apollo has already warned us that
有可能在那个地带遭遇赛昂人
Cylon encounter in the region is probable.
阿波罗上尉有没有打算要告诉我们一些我们还不知道的事?
Has Capt. Apollo managed to tell us anything we don't already know?
他负责这次任务
He is in charge of this mission.
他是仅次于我的二把手
He is second in command only to myself.
我强烈建议你最好记住这点  麦尔先生
I strongly encourage you to remember that, Mr. Meier.
无论有多大风险和后果 我还是要去
Whatever the risks, whatever the consequences, I am going anyway.
我意已决
I am committed.
伯奇上尉  我是卡拉狄加
DUALLA ON RADIO: Capt. Birch, Galactica.
你们可以进行射击与操纵训练了  请确认
You're cleared for target exercise maneuvers, acknowledge.
卡拉狄加  我是队长  照办
BIRCH ON RADIO: Galactica. Leader, Wilco.
所有蝮蛇战机听好  我是空军指挥官
CAG to all Vipers.
按计划进行精确性射击训练
We're initiating our precision-firing exercise as planned.
热狗你先来  小凯准备
Hotdog, you're first up. Kat, on deck.
队长  我是热狗  目标清楚 执行肉眼射击
HOTDOG ON RADIO: Leader, Hotdog. Cleared to target, executing eyeball run
三  二  一  发射
on three, two, one, away.
靠  只击中了边!
HOTDOG: Frak! Winged it.
加油  各位  我知道这只是演习
BIRCH: Come on, people, I know this is just a drill,
但大家要提起精神来
but let's look sharp out there.
热狗  我知道你能做得更好 我们再来一遍
Hotdog, I know you can do a lot better. Let's try it again.
看这次能否正中靶心
See if you can put the next one in the X-ring.
准备完毕
Cleared hot.
进行下次发射
HOTDOG: Ready for another pass.
队长  我是小凯 我想确认是否可以进行攻击练习
Leader, Kat. I'm confirming that I'm cleared for my attack run.
可以吗?
Am I clear?
执行肉眼射击
Executing eyeball run.
是的  你可以进行
Affirmative, you're clear.
向前  武器准备
Rolling in. Weapons hot.
队长  我是小凯 你是说可以了吗?
KAT: Leader, Kat. Did you say all clear?
我说过可以了
BIRCH: I said all clear.
好  收到
Okay, roger that.
来吧  宝贝
Let's go, baby.
开始了  三  二  一  发射
HOTDOG: Here we go! Three, two, one, away!
队长  我开始扫射
KAT: Leader, beginning strafing run.
小凯  你在干什么?
Kat, what are you doing?
你说我可以进行攻击练习呀
You said I'm clear for my attack run.
热狗在进行攻击练习
Hotdog is cleared for his attack run.
什么?热狗?
What? Hotdog?
回撤!小凯!快!快!快!
Back off, Kat! Now! Now! Now!
我的天!
Oh, my gods!
真帅!砰的一声!看到了没?
Yeah! Bang on! Did you see that?
砰的一声?  热狗  你他妈个白痴! 差点害死我了!
Bang on? Hotdog, you frakking idiot! You almost got me killed!
你在说什么啊?
HOTDOG: What are you talking about?
伯奇  你说我可以了!
KAT: Birch, you said I was clear!
蝮蛇战机听好  我是队长
BIRCH: All Vipers, this is Leader.
重复 所有蝮蛇战机  我是队长
Repeat, all Vipers, this is Leader.
返回卡拉狄加  返回卡拉狄加
Report back to Galactica. Report back to Galactica.
干!
Frak!
我知道你的感受  我懂
I know how you feel, I get it.
可我没有开枪打他  不是我开的枪
But I didn't shoot him, okay? It wasn't me.
你们都是一路货色
You're all the same.
你不知道你在说什么
You don't know what the hell you're talking about.
那也许我不该再说了
Then maybe I'm done talking.
我看今天的事已经够多的了
I think there's been enough of that today.
你是最不配告诉我该如何行事的人
You are the last one that should be telling me what to do
瞧你做的那些特技?
after the stunt you pulled.
偷了赛昂突袭机 拍拍屁股跑到了卡布里卡?
Stealing the Cylon Raider and then tearing ass back to Caprica?
恩  就因为你是军纪严明的人  是吧?
Yeah, I guess you're clearly the poster boy for military discipline, huh?
你并不了解我在卡布里卡上的情况
You know what, you have no idea what happened to me on Caprica.
所以当你站在这里耍官威的时候  好好想
So while you're standing here polishing off your halo, consider for a second
你可能根本就不知道你在说什么
that you may not have any damned idea what the hell you're talking about,
上尉
Captain.
罗丝琳的所作所为是不计后果的  我们现在有了自己的舰队
MEIER: What Roslin's doing is reckless. We have our own fleet now.
我们还要装作听从领导到什么时候?
How much longer do we need to keep playing follow the leader?
我们有了舰队是因为人们相信 罗丝琳会带领他们到达地球
We have a fleet because people believe Roslin's going to lead them to Earth.
她是个骗子
She's a fraud.
你是不相信她的  对吧?
You don't believe her, do you?
对  但我相信神话的力量
No, but I believe in the power of myth.
我和你一样不想拿性命去冒险
I'm not interested in risking our lives any more than you are,
但很明显她不会被说服
but she's clearly not gonna be talked out of this.
到了最后  是总统  还是先知 已经无关紧要了
And in the end, president or prophet, it doesn't really matter.
她仍需要一名指挥官  统领整个舰队的人
She still needs a commander, a man in charge of the fleet.
拿着枪的人才说了算
The man with the guns makes the rules.
如果她所选定的舰队领导人不是你  怎么办?
What if she decides you're not the man to be in charge of the fleet?
如果她心里早已有了人选  怎么办?
What if she has someone else in mind?
一个已经和她很亲近的人  像是某个上尉?
Someone already close to her, like a certain captain?
就算你是对的  在某种程度上…
Let's say you're right, that on some level,
在以他们信仰经文的基础上
based on their belief in the scriptures,
舰队需要劳拉·罗丝琳才能团结到一起
the fleet needs Laura Roslin in order to stay in line.
所以我们就要尽力让罗丝琳在科波上活下来
So we do what we must in order to keep Roslin safe on the surface of Kobol.
但...
But...
但是...
But?
你说得对
You're right.
完全正确
You're absolutely right.
我怎么就没想到?
How could I have not have seen that?
我要让这支舰队踏上自由之路
I want to set this fleet on a path to freedom.
这是当然
Of course.
我要实现我所许下的承诺 给他们带来自由
I want to deliver unto them the liberty we've promised.
我们要走的路还很长  我的朋友
We are far from daylight, my friend.
经文上说我们中的一些人会死在科波上
The scriptures say some of us will die on Kobol.
尤其是那个人
One man in particular.
补给船
BIRCH: Tank to Striker.
你偏离中线了
Your approach is a little off the center line.
补给船  把你的增量系数设到0.35  确认
Striker, reset your delta to 0.35, acknowledge.
我是补给船  我的接近速度怎么样?
STRIKER: Striker, how's my approach speed?
你的角度太小  调整
BIRCH: Tanker to Striker. Your angle vectors are too steep. Adjust.
重复  你的角度太小  调整
I repeat, your angle vectors are too steep. Adjust.
加油机  向上10分之一距离
STRIKER: Tanker, request heading, one-tenth of the way.
他在干什么?
What is he doing?
我是加油机
BIRCH: This is Tanker.
告诉他减速
Tell him to cut his speed.
这次又怎么了?
What is it this time?
你来的正好
I'm glad you're here.
伯奇正在协调飞船再补给
Birch is coordinating the ships for refueling,
但书本上最简单的行动被他弄得一团糟
but he's making a mess out of what should be the simplest op in the book!
进行多久了?
How long has he been at it?
到现在4个小时了
About four hours now.
长官  他太缺乏经验了
Sir, he's too green.
他不顾近接和入港的速度
He's blowing the approach and the docking speeds,
错过了减速伞  线与线的认识相混肴 上面一团糟
he's missing the drogues, he's bunching the lines. It's a mess out there.
你也知道  这不是他第一次把事情搞砸了
As you know, this isn't the first screw-up.
恩  我知道
Yes, I know.
我知道他是你器重的人
I realize that he is your guy.
但他不是阿波罗
But he's no Apollo.
移向709…
STRIKER: Moving on 709...
我还想咱们到底什么时候能打场比赛呢
I was wondering when we'd finally get a little R and R around here.
老天  好累
Oh, boy.
把球还我好吗?
Can I have my ball back?
怎么?我玩会儿不行啊?
What, I can't hold it?
请把球还我好吗?
Can I have my ball back, please?
这"金字塔"比赛用球到底哪儿来的？
Where'd you get a Pyramid ball, anyway?
卡布里卡
Caprica.
把球还我好吗  李?
Can I have my ball back, Lee?
恩  当然可以
Yeah, sure.
李?
Lee.
留着吧
Keep it.
拜托  卡拉   少来啦  我开玩笑的
Hey, come on, Kara. For frak's sake, I'm just kidding around.
好了  给  给你
All right, here, it's all yours.
可以拿球回家啦
You can take your ball and go home now.
反正是一件傻事
The whole thing's stupid anyway.
怎么了  卡拉?
What's up with you, Kara?
有什么想说的吗?
Anything you want to talk about?
不想
Nope.
嗯
Hmm.
肯定很难受吧  回到了卡布里卡
Must have been hard, being back on Caprica,
回到了家
being home.
大概在那里看到了一些让人难受的事
Probably saw some tough things back there.
反正明天这一切都会有个结果
Anyway, tomorrow this whole thing's gonna end, one way or another.
能否找到古墓 能否找到通往地球的道路
We find the Tomb or we don't. We find a way to Earth or we don't.
我只想让你知道  我是你的朋友  我爱你
I just want you to know, Kara, that I'm your friend. I love you.
你有什么想说的
If there's anything you want to talk about,
想吐露你的心声  我都会支持你  听你说
anything you wanna get off your chest, then I'm here for you.
总之  你什么时候想说了  告诉我就行
Anyway, whenever you wanna talk just let me know.
中间那句话是什么来着?
What was that middle part again?
什么意思?
What do you mean?
你是说你爱我吗?
Did you say you love me?
呃…
Well...
李·阿达玛爱我?
Lee Adama loves me.
不  我的意思是
No. All I meant was...
不  说真的   说得人心暖暖的
No, seriously, very sweet.
你爱我
You love me.
不  你爱我
No, you love me.
不能食言  说话算话
You can't take it back. There's no take-backs.
你做梦吧你  卡拉    你爱我
You're dreaming it, Kara. You love me.
你在做梦  你爱我
You're dreaming it. You love me.
做白日梦
Dreamer. Mmm-hmm.
好了
Okay.
我是补给船  看不到燃料翼梁
This is Striker. I'm having trouble getting a visual on the fueling spar.
你能改变方向吗?
Can you redirect?
加油站  补给船速度太快
Gas station, Striker's coming in way too hot.
你要补偿增量  现在开始
EMMITT: You gotta back off your delta, like right now.
收到  保持风向角
STRIKER: Roger that. Correcting approach angle.
你没听到了吗?补偿增量
EMMITT: Didn't you hear us? Back off your delta.
你靠得太近了!听到了吗?
You're too close! Are you listening?
好   我们没靠太近
Okay. BIRCH: We are not too close.
补给船  保持目标   取消行动
Striker, remain on target. Abort. Abort the op.
招回船只
Recall the ships.
参与燃料补给的各船注意 我是卡拉狄加  取消任务
Galactica, all ships involved in fuel unrep, abort mission.
重复  取消燃料补给
Say again, abort fuel unrep.
猛禽号返回基地  确认
Raptors, return to base, acknowledge.
照办  卡拉狄加  取消任务
BIRCH: Wilco, Galactica. Aborting mission.
该死!
Damn it!
收到  卡拉狄加说取消近接
BIRCH: Roger that. Galactica says abort approach.
调整角度  返回
Adjust angle vector, full reverse.
补给船  你仍在相撞轨道上
Striker, you're still on a collision course.
左舵  开启推进器  后撤  后撤
Put your helm hard left, full reverse thrusters, back off.
小心!
Look out!
卡拉狄加  我是艾美特  补给船完好无泄露
EMMITT: Galactica, Emmitt. Tanker's intact.
没有无线电联系  但在侧旋
No wireless contact, but it's in an axis spin
看起来确实有些损坏
and there does appear to be some damage.
呼叫救援队  告诉他们登上补给船
Away rescue team, tell them to board the tanker
修复导航控制
and restore navigational control.
呼叫救援队到046界
MAN: Away rescue team, to section 046.
给
Here.
以备不时之需
You never know when you might need to defend yourself.
在这里
Here we go.
"烈焰追赶着他们  科波上的人们有一个选择
"And the blaze pursued them, and the people of Kobol had a choice
登上巨舰或是踏上山中布满岩石的大路
"to board the great ship or take the high road through the rocky ridge. "
各部落首领在雅典娜之墓里
"And the body of each tribe's leader was offered to the gods
把他们的身体献给了神"
"in the Tomb of Athena. "
是的  一字不差
Yes. Precisely.
"巨舰"就是大帆船
And the great ship was a galleon that departed from here,
从我们现在所处的位置起航的
where we're standing.
"它载着13个殖民地的创始人去完成他们的宿命"
And it took the founders of the 13 colonies to their destiny.
"没有登上大帆船的人踏上了...
And those that didn't board the galleon took the high road,
那条通往古墓布满岩石的山中大路"
the rocky ridge that led to the Tomb.
走吧
Let's move.
路旁应该有墓石作为标记
The path is supposed to be marked by gravestones.
那里有些什么东西
There's something there.
等一下!
Wait!
后撤!后撤!
Get back! Get back!
莎伦  莎伦  找护体
HELO: Sharon! Sharon, take cover!
换
Switch.
漂亮  弹药!
Nice one. Ammo!
给
Here.
李!别去!
Lee, no!
不是吧
You gotta be frakking kidding me.
不坏啊
Not bad.
有意思
ADAMA: It's interesting.
背叛居然能让人这么揪心
Betrayal has such a powerful grip on the mind.
几乎和大蟒一样
It's almost like a python.
可以挤压出你的一切思想
It can squeeze out all other thought,
窒息一切情感  直到...
suffocate all other emotion, until
一切都已死去  只留下暴怒
everything is dead except for the rage.
我不是说愤怒
I'm not talking about anger.
而是暴怒
I'm talking about rage.
我能感受得到  就在这里
I can feel it, right here,
像是要裂开一样
like it's gonna burst.
觉得自己想去大喊一声
I feel like I wanna scream,
事实上现在就想去喊
right now, matter of fact.
我可以说句话吗?
If I may say something...
有话直说  小杜
Speak your mind, Dee.
我认为问题不在于别人背叛了你
I don't think the problem is that you've been betrayed.
而是你感到无助
I think it's that you feel helpless.
你中枪了  你受伤了  无法去做些什么
You were shot, you were injured, you couldn't do anything.
不要为我找借口
Don't make excuses for me.
当你终于有机会去做些事的时候
And when you finally had a chance to do something...
抱歉  我这么做
I'm sorry I did this.
你让我们失望了
...you let us down.
你让我们大失所望
You let us down.
你做出过承诺  对我们大家做出过承诺
You made a promise, to all of us
答应我们去找到地球  为我们大家找一个家
to find Earth, to find us a home, together.
总统怎么做都无所谓  李怎么做没关系
It doesn't matter what the President did, or even what Lee did.
因为只要我们分开一天
Because every day that we remain apart
这一天就代表你违背了你的承诺
is a day that you've broken your promise.
那些船上的人是他们自己做的决定
People aboard those ships made their own decision.
是他们的决定  而不是我的决定
It was their decision, not mine.
谢谢你  中士
Thank you, Petty Officer.
你可以走了
You may leave now.
你找我来谈话  长官
You asked to talk to me, sir.
也许是你认为我不会说些什么
Maybe because you think that I don't have anything to say.
但我却有话要说
But I do.
是疗伤的时候了  指挥官
It's time to heal the wounds, Commander.
人们已被分开了
People have been divided.
我说过  够了
I said, that's enough.
妻离子散
Children are separated from their parents.
血的代价
A cost in blood.
我们走吧  总统女士
Let's go, Madam President.
盖塔先生
ADAMA: Mr. Gaeta.
立即把一切有关科波的侦察资料送到我房间里来
I want to see all recon material on Kobol immediately in my quarters.
是  长官
Aye, sir.
科波?
TIGH: Kobol?
是的
Yes.
我要让舰队重新凝聚到一起
I'm putting the fleet back together.
我要让我的家人重聚
I'm putting our family back together.
这一切到此结束了
This ends now.